Fixed & Synced by bozxphd. Enjoy The Flick
- Mama!
- We know.
Jyn, gather your things. It's time.
- Hello?
- Saw, it's Lyra.
It's happened. He's come for us.
You know what to do.
Jyn, come here.
Remember, whatever I do,
I do it to protect you.
Say you understand.
I understand.
I love you, Stardust.
I love you, too, Papa.
Galen.
Go.
Jyn.
You know where to go, don't you?
Trust the Force.
You're a hard man to find, Galen.
But farming...
Really? Man of your talents?
It's a peaceful life.
It's lonely, I imagine.
Since Lyra died, yes.
Oh.
Oh...
My condolences.
Search the house.
What is it you want?
The work has stalled.
I need you to come back.
I won't do it, Krennic.
We were on the verge of greatness.
We were this close
to providing peace
and security for the galaxy.
You're confusing peace with terror.
Well,
you have to start somewhere.
I'd be of no help, Krennic.
My mind just isn't what it was.
I have trouble remembering.
Even simple things.
Galen...
You're an inspired scientist,
but you're a terrible liar.
Now, I admire the effort.
I really do.
Oh, look, here's Lyra,
back from the dead.
It's a miracle.
Stop!
Oh, Lyra,
troublesome as ever.
You're not taking him.
No, of course I'm not. I'm taking you all.
You'll all come. You, your child.
You'll all live in comfort.
As hostages.
As heroes of the Empire.
Lyra. Put it down.
Think very carefully.
- You will never win.
- Do it.
Lyra!
They have a child!
Find it!
My child!
Come.
We have a long ride ahead of us.
Check in security,
cell block 4227.
4227.
TK-62, XX-25900.
I was about to leave.
I came as fast as I could.
I have to get back on board.
Walk with me.
Back to Jedha?
They'll leave without me.
Easy! You have news from Jedha.
Come on.
An Imperial pilot,
one of the cargo drivers
he defected yesterday.
He's telling people
they're making a weapon.
The kyber crystals,
that's what they're for.
What kind of weapon?
- Look, I have to go.
- What kind of weapon?
A planet killer! That's what he called it!
A planet killer?
Someone named Erso sent him.
Some old friend of Saw's.
Galen Erso? Was it?
I don't know!
They were looking for Saw when we left.
- Who else knows about this?
- I have no idea.
It's all falling apart.
Saw's right.
There's spies everywhere.
What's all this?
Come on, let's see some scandocs.
Yeah, of course. Just... My gloves.
No!
What have you done?
Troopers down. Section 9.
Are you crazy?
I'll never climb out of here. My arm!
Get out of the way.
Move! Move!
Hey. Calm down. Calm down.
It will be all right.
Is that him?
He looks kind of different
to how I imagined.
Okay.
So you're Saw Gerrera?
Saw Gerrera?
No?
Okay, we're just wasting time
that we don't have.
I need to speak to Saw Gerrera.
I keep telling them.
Before it's too late.
We're out here in the middle of nowhere.
We need to get to Jedha City.
What part of "urgent message"
do you guys not understand?
We are all on the same side.
If you just see past
the uniform for a minute.
What now?
I don't know. Must be another pickup.
I thought we had everybody.
All clear, sir.
Hallik! Liana Hallik!
Her.
You wanna get out of here?
Hey! What about me?
Give me the keys! Give me the keys!
Congratulations. You are being rescued.
Please do not resist.
LU-28,
report to maintenance level 4.
You're currently
calling yourself Liana Hallik.
Is that correct?
Possession of unsanctioned weapons.
Forgery of Imperial documents.
Aggravated assault.
Escape from custody.
Resisting arrest.
Imagine if the Imperial authorities
had found out...
who you really were, Jyn Erso.
That is your given name, is it not?
Jyn Erso, daughter of Galen Erso?
A known Imperial collaborator
in weapons development.
What is this?
It's a chance
for you to make a fresh start.
We think you might be able to help us.
This is Captain Cassian Andor,
Rebel Intelligence.
When was the last time
you were in contact with your father?
15 years ago.
Any idea where he's been all that time?
I like to think he's dead.
Makes things easier.
Easier than what? That he's been a tool
of the Imperial war machine?
I've never had the luxury
of political opinions.
Really?
When was your last contact
with Saw Gerrera?
It's been a long time.
But he'll remember you, though.
Wouldn't he?
He might agree to meet you,
if you came as a friend.
We're up against the clock here, girl,
so if there's nothing to talk about,
we'll just put you back
where we found you.
I was a child.
Saw Gerrera saved my life. He raised me.
But I have no idea where he is.
I haven't seen him in years.
We know how to find him.
That's not our problem.
What we need is someone
who gets us through the door
without being killed.
You're all rebels, aren't you?
Yes,
but Saw Gerrera is an extremist.
He's been fighting on his own
since he broke with the Rebellion.
His militancy has caused the Alliance
a great many problems.
We have no choice now but to try
and mend that broken trust.
What does this have to do
with my father?
There's an Imperial defector
in Jedha. A pilot.
He's been held by Saw Gerrera.
He's claiming the Emperor
is creating a weapon
with the power to destroy entire planets.
The pilot says
he was sent by your father.
We need to stop this weapon
before it is finished.
Captain Andor's mission
is to authenticate the pilot's story.
And then, if possible, find your father.
It appears he is critical
to the development
of this super weapon.
Given the gravity of the situation
and your history with Saw,
we're hoping that he will
help us locate your father
and return him
to the Senate for testimony.
And if I do it?
We'll make sure you go free.
Captain Andor.
I'm K-2SO.
I'm a reprogrammed Imperial droid.
I remember you.
I see the Council is
sending you with us to Jedha.
Apparently so.
That is a bad idea. I think so,
and so does Cassian.
What do I know?
My specialty is just
strategic analysis.
Galen Erso is vital to
the Empire's weapons program.
Forget what you heard in there.
There will be no extraction.
You find him...
you kill him.
Then and there.
Shuttle number LMTR-20.
Prepare for takeoff while
we check your authorization.
You met K-2?
Charming.
He tends to say
whatever comes into his circuits.
It's a byproduct of the reprogram.
Why does she get a blaster and I don't?
- What?
- I know how to use it.
That's what I'm afraid of. Give it to me.
We're going to Jedha.
That's a war zone.
That's not the point. Where'd you get it?
I found it.
I find that answer
vague and unconvincing.
Trust goes both ways.
You're letting her keep it?
Would you like to know the probability
of her using it against you?
It's high.
Let's get going.
It's very high.
Lies!
Deceptions!
Let's see it.
"Bodhi Rook. Cargo pilot."
- Local boy, huh?
- Uh-huh.
Okay. I can hear you.
He didn't capture me. I came
here myself. I defected.
I defected.
Every day, more lies.
Lies? Would I risk everything for a lie?
No, we don't have time for this.
I have to speak to Saw Gerrera
before it's too late.
Okay.
Sorry, you're...
Um...
That's for you.
And I gave it to them.
They did not find it!
I gave it to them.
Uh, Galen Erso.
He told me to find you.
Bor Gullet.
Uh, Bor Gullet?
What? Wait!
Galen Erso sent me!
He told me to find you.
Most unfortunate about
the security breach on Jedha,
Director Krennic.
After so many setbacks
and delays, and now this.
We've heard word of rumors
circulating through the city.
Apparently, you've lost
a rather talkative cargo pilot.
If the Senate gets wind of our project,
countless systems
will flock to the Rebellion.
When the battle station is
finished, Governor Tarkin...
the Senate will be of little concern.
When has become now,
Director Krennic.
The Emperor will tolerate
no further delay.
You have made time
an ally of the Rebellion.
I suggest we solve
both problems simultaneously...
with an immediate test of the weapon.
Failure will find you explaining why
to a far less patient audience.
I will not fail.
What's the matter, Jyn?
You look frightened.
I'll always protect you.
Stardust.
Don't ever change.
Trust.
Galen.
We're coming into orbit.
You have controls.
That's Jedha.
Or what's left of it.
We find Saw, we find your father.
What's with the Destroyer?
It's because of
your old friend, Saw Gerrera.
He's been attacking
the cargo shipments.
What are they bringing in?
It's what are they taking out.
Kyber crystal. All they can get.
We wondered why
they were stripping the temple.
Now we know.
It's the fuel for the weapon.
The weapon your father's building.
Maybe we should leave
target practice behind.
Are you talking about me?
She's right. We need to blend in.
Stay with the ship.
I can blend in. I'm an Imperial droid.
The city is under Imperial occupation.
Half the people here
wanna reprogram you.
The other half wanna
put a hole in your head.
I'm surprised
you're so concerned with my safety.
I'm not.
I'm just worried they might
miss you and hit me.
Doesn't sound so bad to me.
Bor Gullet can feel your thoughts.
No lie is safe.
What have you really
brought me, cargo pilot?
Bor Gullet will know the truth.
The unfortunate side effect
is that one tends...
to lose one's mind.
No!
Hey.
You just watch yourself.
Wait. No, no.
Sorry, sir.
We don't want any trouble. Sorry.
Come on. Come on.
Citizens of Jedha.
You must come forward with information
of the location
of this missing cargo pilot.
A reward of 600 credits
for the information shall be awarded.
I had a contact.
One of Saw's Rebels.
But he's just gone missing.
H is sister will be looking for him.
The temple's been destroyed,
but she'll be there waiting.
We'll give her your name
and hope that gets us
a meeting with Saw.
Hope?
Yeah. Rebellions are built on hope.
Hands where I can see them.
Get over there.
Show me some identification.
Check inside.
Is this all because of your pilot?
May the Force
of others be with you.
Wait for me.
May the Force
of others be with you.
May the Force of others be with you.
Would you trade that necklace
for a glimpse into your future?
Yes.
I'm speaking to you.
I'm Chirrut îmwe.
How did you know
I was wearing a necklace?
For that answer, you must pay.
What do you know
about kyber crystals?
My father, he...
He said they powered
the Jedi's lightsabers.
Jyn.
Come on. Let's go.
The strongest stars
have hearts of kyber.
Let's go.
We're not here to make friends.
Who are they?
The Guardians of the Whills.
Protectors of the Kyber Temple.
But there's nothing left to protect.
So now they're just
causing trouble for everybody.
You seem awfully tense all of a sudden.
We have to hurry.
This town is ready to blow.
Citizens of the Empire...
Imperial forces tirelessly fight
Saw Gerrera's reign of terror...
over the people of this beloved city.
Truth and justice
are the tools of the Empire.
Tell me you have a backup plan.
Incoming!
Looks like we found Saw's rebels.
Up there!
Jyn, no!
Hit the terrorist.
Get out of there!
Kyber...
Come on!
This way!
Cassian!
Did you know that wasn't me?
Yeah. Of course.
I thought I told you to stay on the ship.
You did. But I thought it was boring,
and you were in trouble.
There were a lot of explosions...
- for two people blending in.
- Freeze!
You're right.
I should just wait on the ship.
Halt. Stop right there.
Where are you taking these prisoners?
- These are prisoners.
- Yes. Where are you taking them?
I am taking them
to imprison them in prison.
- He's taking us to...
- Quiet!
And there's a fresh one
if you mouth off again.
- We'll take them from here.
- That's okay.
If you could just point me
in the right direction,
I can take them, I'm sure.
- I've taken them this far.
- Hey, wait a second.
- Take them away.
- Wait.
You can't take them away.
You. Stay here.
We need to check your diagnostics.
Diagnostics?
I'm capable of running
my own diagnostics,
thank you very much.
Let them pass in peace.
The Force is with me.
And I am with the Force.
And I fear nothing.
For all is as the Force wills it.
Hey, stop right there.
He's blind.
Is he deaf?
I said stop right there!
Is your foot all right?
You almost shot me.
You're welcome.
Clear of hostiles.
- One hostile.
- He's with us.
They're all right.
Thanks.
Cassian, I'm sorry about the slap.
Go back to the ship. Wait for my call.
Is he a Jedi?
There are no Jedi here anymore.
Only dreamers like this fool.
The Force did protect me.
I protected you.
Can you get us to Saw Gerrera?
Can't you see?
We are no friends of the Empire.
Anyone who kills me or my friends
will answer to Saw Gerrera.
Because I'm the daughter of Galen Erso.
Are you kidding me? I'm blind.
I'm one with the Force,
the Force is with me.
You pray?
I'm one with the Force,
the Force is with me.
Really?
I'm one with the Force,
the Force is with me.
He's praying for the door to open.
It bothers him because
he knows it's possible.
Baze Malbus was once the most
devoted Guardian of us all.
I'm beginning to think the Force and I
have different priorities.
Relax, Captain.
We've been in worse cages
than this one.
This is the first for me.
There is more than
one sort of prison, Captain.
I sense that you carry yours
wherever you go.
Jyn.
Is it really you?
I can't believe it!
Must be quite a surprise.
Are we not still friends?
The last time I saw you,
you gave me a knife
and loaded blaster...
and told me to wait
in a bunker till daylight.
I knew you were safe.
You left me behind.
You were already
the best soldier in my cadre.
- I was 16!
- I was protecting you!
You dumped me!
You were the daughter of
an Imperial science officer.
People were starting to figure that out.
People who wanted to
use you as a hostage.
Not a day goes by...
that I don't think of you.
But today...
of all days...
It's a trap.
Isn't it?
What?
The pilot.
The message.
All of it.
Did they send you?
Did you come here...
to kill me?
There's not much of me left.
The Alliance wants my father.
They think he sent you
a message about a weapon.
I guess they think by sending me,
you might actually help them out.
So what is it that you want, Jyn?
They wanted an introduction,
they've got it.
I'm out now.
Rest of you can do what you want.
You care not about the cause?
The cause?
Seriously?
The Alliance...
the rebels, whatever it is
you're calling yourself these days...
all it's ever brought me is pain.
You can stand to see the Imperial flag
reign across the galaxy?
It's not a problem if you don't look up.
I have something to show you.
Come.
The Emperor is awaiting my report.
One would hope that he and Lord Vader
might've been here
for such an occasion.
And I thought it prudent to save you
from any potential embarrassment.
Your concern's hardly warranted.
If saying it would only make it so.
All Imperial forces
have been evacuated...
and I stand ready to destroy
the entire moon.
That won't be necessary.
We need a statement, not a manifesto.
The Holy City will be enough for today.
Target Jedha City.
Prepare single reactor ignition.
- Sir, we're in position...
- Fire!
Commence primary ignition.
Who's the one in the next cell?
What?
Where?
An Imperial pilot.
- Pilot?
- I'm gonna kill him!
- No, no. No, wait!
- Come here!
No!
Back off! Back off!
Okay, okay.
Are you the pilot?
Hey. Hey. Are you the pilot?
The shuttle pilot?
Pilot?
What's wrong with him?
Galen Erso.
You know that name?
I brought the message. I'm the pilot.
I'm the pilot.
Okay. Good.
Now where is Galen Erso?
Stand by.
This is the message I was sent.
Saw, if you are watching this...
then perhaps there's a chance
to save the Alliance.
Perhaps there's a chance
to explain myself...
and, though I don't dare
hope for too much...
a chance for Jyn, if she's alive...
if you can possibly find her...
to let her know that my love
for her has never faded...
and how desperately I've missed her.
Jyn, my Stardust...
I can't imagine what you think of me.
When I was taken,
I faced some bitter truths.
I was told that soon enough
Krennic would have you as well.
As time went by...
I knew that you were either dead...
or so well hidden that
he would never find you.
I knew if I had refused to work,
if I took my own life...
it would only be a matter of time
before Krennic realized...
he no longer needed me
to complete the project.
So I did the one thing nobody expected.
I lied.
I learned to lie.
I played the part of a beaten man
resigned to the sanctuary of his work.
I made myself indispensable...
and all the while, I laid
the groundwork of my revenge.
We call it the Death Star.
There is no better name...
and the day is coming soon
when it will be unleashed.
I've placed a weakness
deep within the system...
a flaw so small and powerful,
they will never find it.
But, Jyn...
Jyn, if you're listening, my beloved...
so much of my life has been wasted.
I try to think of you only
in the moments when I'm strong...
because the pain of
not having you with me...
your mother, our family.
The pain of that loss
is so overwhelming...
I risk failing even now.
It's just so hard not to think of you.
Think of where you are...
my Stardust.
Saw...
the reactor module, that's the key.
That's the place I've laid my trap.
It's well hidden and unstable.
One blast to any part of it
will destroy the entire station.
You'll need the plans...
the structural plans for the Death Star,
to find the reactor.
I know there's a complete
engineering archive...
in the data vault
at the Citadel Tower on Scarif.
Any pressurized explosion
to the reactor module...
will set off a chain reaction
that will destroy the entire station.
Go, go!
K-2, K-2! Where are you?
There you are.
I'm standing by as you requested...
although there's a problem
on the horizon.
There's no horizon.
Locate our position.
Bring that ship in here, now!
Where are you going?
I gotta find Jyn.
Get the pilot, we need him!
All right.
I'll get the pilot.
Pilot.
No, no, no!
Let's go.
Jyn!
Hey.
We gotta go.
I know where your father is.
Go with him, Jyn.
You must go!
Come with us.
I will run no longer.
- Come on.
- But you must save yourself.
- Go!
There's no time!
Save the Rebellion!
Save the dream.
Oh, it's beautiful.
Chirrut, let's go!
Come on!
Let's get out of here!
Get us out of here!
Punch it!
I'm not very optimistic about our odds.
Not now, K.
Come on!
Punch it.
I haven't completed my calculations.
I'll make them for you.
I believe I owe you
an apology, Director Krennic.
Your work exceeds all expectations.
And you'll tell the Emperor as much?
I will tell him that his patience
with your misadventures...
has been rewarded with a weapon
that will bring a swift end
to the Rebellion.
And that that was only an inkling
of its destructive potential.
I will tell him that I will be
taking control over the weapon...
I first spoke of years ago
effective immediately.
We stand here amidst my achievement.
Not yours!
I'm afraid the recent security breaches...
have laid bare your inadequacies
as a military director.
The breaches have been filled.
Jedha has been silenced.
You think this pilot acted alone?
He was dispatched from
the installation on Eadu...
Galen Erso's facility.
Oh, we'll see about this.
A coded message
from Captain Andor, sir.
"Weapon confirmed."
"Jedha destroyed."
"Mission target located
on Eadu, please advise."
Destroyed?
Proceed.
Tell him my orders still stand.
Tell him to proceed with haste...
and keep to the plan.
We have no idea
what he's building for the Empire.
We have to kill Galen Erso
while we have the chance.
Baze, tell me.
All of it?
The whole city?
Tell me.
All of it.
Understood.
Set course for Eadu.
Setting course for Eadu.
Is that where my father is?
I think so.
So you're Galen's daughter?
You know him?
I am Bodhi, the pilot.
You brought the message.
Yes.
Your father...
he said I could get right by myself.
He said I could make it right...
if I was brave enough...
to listen to what was in my heart.
Do something about it.
Guess it was too late.
It wasn't too late.
Seems pretty late to me.
No.
We can beat the people who did this.
My father's message, I've seen it.
They call it the Death Star.
But they have no idea...
there's a way to defeat it.
You're wrong about my father.
He did build it.
Because he knew
they'd do it without him.
My father made a choice.
He sacrificed himself for the Rebellion.
He's rigged a trap inside it.
That's why he sent you,
to bring that message.
Where is it?
Where's the message?
It was a hologram.
You have that message, right?
Everything happened so fast.
Did you see it?
You don't believe me?
I'm not the one you've got to convince.
I believe her.
That's good to know.
What kind of trap?
You said your father made a trap.
The reactor.
He's placed a weakness there.
He's been hiding it for years.
He said if you can blow the reactor,
the module,
the whole system goes down.
You need to send word to the Alliance.
I've done that.
They have to know
there's a way to destroy this thing.
They have to go to Scarif
to get the plans.
I can't risk sending that.
We're in the heart of Imperial territory.
Then we'll find him and bring him back.
And he can tell them himself.
Course set for Eadu, sir.
I'm one with the Force,
the Force is with me.
20 degrees to the right.
10 degrees up.
Lower, lower, lower. Lower!
Are you sure this is the way?
They have landing trackers here.
They have patrol squadrons.
You've got to stay
in the canyon. Keep it low.
Watch your right!
There's a 26% chance of failure.
How much farther?
I don't know, I'm not sure.
I never really come this way.
But we're close, we're close. I know that.
Now, there's a 35% chance of failure.
I don't wanna know.
Thank you!
I understand.
Now! Put it down, now!
The wind.
If you keep going,
you'll be right over the shuttle depot.
- Watch out!
- K!
Hold on tight!
We're coming down hard!
Try them again.
I am, sir. We...
The signal's gone dead.
Squadron up.
Target Eadu.
How about now? Check stabilizers.
Bodhi, where's the lab?
The research facility?
Yeah. Where is it?
It's just over that ridge.
That's a shuttle depot
straight ahead of us.
- You are sure of that?
- Yes.
We'll have to hope
there's still an Imperial ship
left to steal.
Here's what we're doing.
Hopefully the storm keeps up
and keeps us hidden down here.
Bodhi, you're coming with me.
We'll go up the ridge and check it out.
I'm coming with you.
No, your father's message.
We can't risk it. You're the messenger.
That's ridiculous,
we all got the message.
Everyone here knows it.
"One blast to the reactor module
"and the whole system goes down."
That's how you said it,
"The whole system goes down."
Get to work fixing our comms.
All I want to do right now
is get a handle on what we're up against.
So we're gonna go very small
and very careful up the rise...
and see what's what.
Let's get outta here.
Does he look like a killer?
No. He has the face of a friend.
Who are you talking about?
Captain Andor.
Why'd you ask that?
What do you mean,
"Does he look like a killer?"
The Force moves darkly
near a creature that's about to kill.
His weapon was
in the sniper configuration.
No, no, no. We've got to go up.
You can't see much from down there.
This way.
I'll be right behind you.
Come on.
Where are you going?
I'm gonna follow Jyn.
Her path is clear.
Alone?
Good luck!
I don't need luck. I have you!
What are they doing?
If Cassian comes back,
we're leaving without them.
You see Erso out there?
We've come too far.
Patience, my friend.
That's him.
That's him. Galen, in the dark suit.
Get back down there
and find us a ride outta here.
- Well, what are you doing?
- You heard me.
You said we came up here
just to have a look.
I'm here, I'm looking. Go.
Hurry!
Excellent news, Galen.
The battle station is complete.
You must be very proud.
Proud as I can be, Krennic.
Gather your engineers.
I have an announcement.
Is that all of them?
Yes.
Gentlemen, one of you...
betrayed the Empire.
One of you has conspired with a pilot...
to send messages to the Rebellion.
And I urge that traitor...
step forward.
Very well...
I'll consider it a group effort then.
Ready!
- No! No!
- Aim!
And fire!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Krennic, stop!
It was me!
They have nothing to do with it.
Spare them.
Fire!
How do I know the weapon is complete?
Let me share with you some details.
Cassian.
Cassian, can you hear me?
I'm here.
You've got it working?
Affirmative, yes.
Although we have a problem.
There's an Alliance squadron
approaching. Clear the area.
No, no, no, no! Tell them to hold off!
Jyn's on that platform.
Jedha...
Saw Gerrera. His band of fanatics...
their Holy City...
the last reminder of the Jedi, gone.
You'll never win.
Now where have I heard that before?
Relay from Captain Andor.
General.
Captain Andor requesting
a delay on squadron support.
Alliance forces on site. Please confirm.
Get the squadron leader on.
Get him on now!
They're already engaged, sir.
Jyn. No.
Return fire! To your stations!
Get our fighters in the air now!
Father!
Roger that. 3 through 7.
Fall back! Fall back!
Director, we need to evacuate.
Papa. Papa, it's me.
It's Jyn.
Jyn?
Stardust.
Papa.
I've seen your message.
The hologram, I've seen it.
It must be destroyed.
I know. I know.
We will.
Jyn.
Look at you.
I have so much to tell you.
Papa.
No.
No! Papa.
Papa, come on!
Over there! Take 'em down.
Come on. Papa. Come on.
Jyn, we gotta go. Come on.
I can't leave him.
Listen to me, he's gone.
Nothing you can do. Come on.
- I can't leave him.
- Come on!
I can't.
Move!
- This way, this way!
- Down!
Come on! Come on!
Well done.
You're a rebel now.
Let's go! Let's go!
Come on, let's move!
Come on, let's get out of here!
Move, move, move!
Okay, K-2. Let's go!
Copy that.
Ion thrusters low until
we've cleared the storm.
Understood.
You lied to me.
You're in shock.
You went up there to kill my father.
You don't know
what you're talking about.
Deny it.
You're in shock and looking
for some place to put it.
I've seen it before.
I bet you have.
They know.
You lied about why we came here
and you lied about why you went up alone.
I had every chance to pull the trigger...
but did I?
Did I?
You might as well have.
My father was living proof...
and you put him at risk.
Those were Alliance bombs
that killed him.
I had orders...
orders that I disobeyed.
But you wouldn't understand that.
Orders?
When you know they're wrong?
You might as well be a Stormtrooper.
What do you know?
We don't all have
the luxury of deciding...
when and where we want to
care about something.
Suddenly the Rebellion is real for you.
Some of us live it.
I've been in this fight
since I was 6 years old.
You're not the only one
who lost everything.
Some of us just decided
to do something about it.
You can't talk your way around this.
I don't have to.
Yavin 4.
Make sure they know
we're coming in with a stolen ship.
Anybody else?
My lord, Director Krennic...
has arrived.
Director Krennic.
Lord Vader.
You seem unsettled.
No...
just pressed for time.
There's a great many things to attend to.
My apologies.
You do have
a great many things to explain.
I delivered the weapon
the Emperor requested.
I deserve an audience...
to make certain that
he understands its remarkable...
potential.
Its power to create problems
has certainly been confirmed.
A city destroyed...
an Imperial facility openly attacked.
It was Governor Tarkin
that suggested the test.
You were not summoned here
to grovel, Director Krennic.
No...
There is no Death Star.
The Senate has been informed...
that Jedha was destroyed
in a mining disaster.
Yes, my lord.
I expect you not to rest until
you can assure the Emperor...
that Galen Erso has not compromised
this weapon in any way.
So I'm still in command?
You'll speak to the Emperor about...
Be careful not to choke
on your aspirations, Director.
We must scatter the fleet.
We have no recourse but to surrender.
Are we really talking
about disbanding something...
that we've worked so hard to create?
We can't just give in!
We joined an alliance,
not a suicide pact.
We've only now managed
to gather our forces.
Gather our forces?
General Draven's already
blown up an Imperial base.
A decision needed to be made!
If it's war you want...
you'll fight alone.
If that's how it's going,
why have an alliance at all?
If she's telling the truth,
we need to act now!
Councilors, please.
It is simple.
The Empire has the means
of mass destruction...
the Rebellion does not.
A Death Star. This is nonsense.
What reason
would my father have to lie?
What benefit would it bring him?
To lure our forces into a final battle
to destroy us once and for all.
Risk everything?
Based on what?
The testimony of a criminal?
The dying words of her father,
an Imperial scientist?
But don't forget
the Imperial pilot.
My father gave his life so that
we may have a chance to defeat this.
So you've told us.
If the Empire has this kind of power,
what chance do we have?
What chance do we have?
The question is "what choice."
Run, hide...
plead for mercy, scatter your forces.
You give way to an enemy this evil
with this much power...
and you condemn the galaxy
to an eternity of submission.
- The time to fight is now!
- Yes.
Every moment you waste
is another step closer
to the ashes of Jedha.
What is she proposing?
Just let the girl speak.
Send your best troops to Scarif.
Send the rebel fleet if you have to.
You need to capture
the Death Star plans
if there's any hope of destroying it.
You're asking us to invade
an Imperial installation...
based on nothing but hope.
Rebellions are built on hope.
There is no hope.
I say we fight.
I say the Rebellion is finished!
I'm sorry, Jyn.
Without the full support of the Council...
the odds are too great.
General Syndulla,
please report to the briefing room.
You don't look happy.
They prefer to surrender.
And you?
She wants to fight.
So do I. We all do.
The Force is strong.
I'm not sure four of us is quite enough.
How many do we need?
What are you talking about?
They were never gonna believe you.
I appreciate the support.
But I do.
I believe you.
We'd like to volunteer.
Some of us...
Well, most of us...
we've all done terrible things
on behalf of the Rebellion.
Spies...
saboteurs, assassins.
Everything I did, I did for the Rebellion.
And every time I walked away...
from something I wanted to forget...
I told myself it was
for a cause that I believed in.
A cause that was worth it.
Without that, we're lost.
Everything we've done
would have been for nothing.
I couldn't face myself if I gave up now.
None of us could.
It won't be comfortable.
It'd be a bit cramped, but we'd all fit.
We could go.
Okay. Gear up.
Grab anything that's not nailed down.
Go, go, go!
Jyn.
I'll be there for you.
Cassian said I had to.
I'm not used to people sticking around
when things go bad.
Welcome home.
May the Force be with us.
Cargo shuttle, read back please.
What's going on out there?
That ship's off-limits.
No one's supposed to be on board
until further instructions.
Yes, yes, we are.
Affirmative.
That's an impounded Imperial ship.
What's your call sign, pilot?
- Um...
- We have to go.
It's, um...
Say something.
Come on.
Rogue.
Rogue One.
Rogue One?
There is no Rogue One!
Well, there is now.
Rogue One, pulling away.
Pulling away.
Despite what the others say,
war is inevitable.
Yes, I agree.
I must return to Alderaan
to inform my people
that there will be no peace.
We will need every advantage.
Your friend...
the Jedi.
He served me well
during the Clone Wars...
and has lived in hiding
since the Emperor's purge.
Yes, I will send for him.
You will need someone you can trust.
I would trust her with my life.
- Captain Antilles.
- Senator.
I have a mission for you, sir.
Okay. We're coming in.
There's a planet-wide defensive shield...
with a single main entry gate.
This shuttle should be equipped with
an access code that allows us through.
Assuming the Empire hasn't
logged it as overdue.
And if they have?
Then they shut the gate.
And we're all annihilated
in the cold, dark vacuum of space.
Not me.
I can survive in space.
Okay.
Here goes.
Cargo shuttle SW-0608
requesting a landing pad.
Cargo shuttle SW-0608,
you're not listed on the arrival schedule.
Acknowledged, Gate Control.
We were rerouted
from Eadu flight station.
Transmitti ng clearance code now.
Transmitting.
Cargo shuttle, SW-0608...
- you are cleared for entry.
- Yes!
Impressive.
I'll tell the others.
Okay.
Tractor
beam test in bays 2 through 8.
Tractor beam test in bays 2 through 8.
SW-0608,
cleared for Landing Pad 9.
Acknowledge, please.
SW-0608 proceeding
to LP 9 as instructed.
Main building
down there, what is it?
That's the Citadel Tower.
They keep all the Imperial
structural archives up there.
If the plans are anywhere,
they'll be there.
And the dish
at the top, what's it for?
I guess it takes a lot of signal
to send those data files out.
Landing track, engaged.
Landing track locked.
We're landing.
We're coming in.
Saw Gerrera used to say...
one fighter with a sharp stick
and nothing left to lose can take the day.
They've no idea we're coming.
They've no reason to expect us.
If we can make it to the ground,
we'll take the next chance.
And the next. On and on until we win...
or the chances are spent.
The Death Star plans are down there.
Cassian, K-2, and I will find them.
We'll find a way to find them.
Melshi...
Pao...
Baze, Chirrut...
you'll take the main squad.
Move east and get wide of the ship.
Find a position between
here and the tower.
Once you get to the best spot...
light the place up.
Make 10 men feel like 100.
And get those troopers away from us.
What should I do?
Keep the engine running.
You're our only way outta here.
Cargo shuttle SW-0608...
be prepared to receive inspection team.
Ready?
Hello.
Hey.
Oh, you're probably
looking for a manifest?
That would be helpful.
It's just down here.
Director Krennic,
we are entering the Scarif shield gate.
General Ramda has been
informed of your arrival.
Good luck...
little sister.
Go! Go now! You're clear!
All right, let's go!
Come on. Move, move, move.
925-H to transport control.
I've got a bad feeling about...
- K!
- Quiet!
What?
We need a map.
Well, I'm sure there's one
just lying about.
You know what you have to do.
One per pad.
Pick your spot.
We wanna draw them out.
I'll call the timing. Go!
Hey, did you hear the rumors?
Yeah, the T-15s
have been marked obsolete.
Oh boy,
it's about time for that.
Hey!
What the...
Director, what brings you to Scarif?
Galen Erso.
I want every dispatch,
every transmission he has ever sent...
called up for inspection.
All of them?
Yes, all of them.
Get started.
K.
Our optimal route to the data vault
places only 89 Stormtroopers
in our path.
We will make it
no more than 33% of the way
before we are killed.
Melshi, talk to me.
Ready. Ready. Standing by.
Light it up.
Come on.
Are we blind?
Deploy the garrison!
Move!
Troopers!
Troopers! Troopers on the left.
Get in! Get in!
Sir, it's Scarif base.
They're reporting a Rebel incursion.
I want to speak with Director Krennic.
He's there, sir. On Scarif.
The original plans for this station
are kept there, are they not?
They are.
Prepare for the jump to hyperspace
and inform Lord Vader.
Can we help you?
That won't be necessary.
Senator!
Stop right there, Private.
Let him speak.
Intercepted Imperial
transmission, ma'am.
Rebels on Scarif.
I need to speak with Admiral Raddus.
He's returned to his ship.
He's going to fight.
No!
Attention, all flight personnel,
please report to
your commanders immediately.
All flight personnel,
please report to
your commanders immediately.
We have been redirected to Scarif.
Pilots, you'll be briefed
by your squadron leaders en route.
May the Force be with you.
Scarif? They're goi ng to Scarif?
Why does nobody
ever tel I me anythi ng, R2?
Move, move, move!
Forward! Forward!
Keep drawing them out!
Pad 12, report to ground.
Coming in on our flank.
We need numbers.
Pad 14,
what's going on down there?
Status please.
All pads report in immediately.
Oh, no.
We have rebels everywhere!
We're taking fire!
Pad 12, Pad 14 request assistance.
This is Pad 2. Pad 2.
I spot 40 rebels heading west on Pad 2.
Get on there. T ell him you're pinned
down by rebels on Pad 5.
This is Pad 5!
We're being overrun! Help us!
Pad 12, Pad 10, Pad 8, please confirm.
Confirm and report.
Get reinforcements down
to Pad 5 immediately!
This is not working, K!
Right hand.
Baze!
- Baze!
- What?
Run!
Karabast! AT-AT!
Move!
This is Admiral Raddus
of the Rebel Alliance.
All squadron leaders, report in.
Admiral, this is Blue Leader standing by.
This is Gold Leader standing by.
This is Red Leader standing by.
Sir, those are rebel ships.
Get Admiral Gorin, immediately!
Director, the rebel fleet,
it's amassing outside the shield.
Lock down the base. Lock it down.
- And close the shield?
- Do it!
Red and Gold Squadrons,
attack formations.
Defend the fleet.
Blue Squadron, get to the surface
before they close that gate.
Copy you, Admiral.
Blue Squadron, on me!
Copy, Blue Leader.
- Copy, Blue Leader.
- We won't have long.
Close the field aperture now! Close it!
Come on, come on, come on!
Pull up!
The rebel fleet has arrived.
What?
There's fighting on the beach.
They've locked down the base.
They've closed the shield gate.
What does that mean?
We're trapped?
We could transmit the plans
to the rebel fleet.
We'd have to get a signal up
to tell them it's coming.
It's the size of the data files.
That's the problem.
They'll never get through.
Someone has to
take that shield gate down.
Bodhi. Bodhi, can you hear me?
Bodhi, tell me you're out there.
Bodhi?
I'm here.
I was standing by.
They've started fighting.
The base is on lockdown.
I know. Listen to me.
The rebel fleet is up there.
You've gotta tell them to
blow a hole in the shield gate...
so we can transmit the plans.
Wait. I can't. I'm not hooked
into the comms tower.
We're not tied in.
It's the only way
we're getting them out of here.
Find a way!
Cover our backs.
You'll need this.
You wanted one, right?
Your behavior, Jyn Erso,
is continually unexpected.
Jyn. Come on.
Sa'kalla!
Fire on my command.
Look!
Get ready. We're gonna have
to go out there.
What are you doing?
They've closed the shield gate.
We're stuck here.
But the rebel fleet are pulling in.
We just have to get a signal
strong enough to get through to them...
and let them know
that we're trapped down here.
For that, we have to connect
to the communications tower.
Now, I can patch us in over here,
the landing pad.
But you have to get on the radio.
Get one of the guys out there
to find a master switch.
Get them to activate the connection
between us and that comms tower.
Okay?
Then go!
What's going on
down there, Lieutenant?
Unknown, sir.
We can't raise them.
All rebel frequencies are blocked.
Keep trying.
Engage those Star Destroyers
and let's start probing that shield!
Yes, sir!
We're going in.
Stay with me.
Schematic bank, data tower two.
How do I find that?
Searching.
I can locate the tape,
but you'll need to use
the handles for extraction.
What am I supposed to do with this?
Whoa!
Well, finally.
Wait! Stop!
The rebels, they went over there.
K, what's going on out there?
There's one.
Ah, well.
Come on!
Red Leader, this is Gold Leader.
We're starting our attack run
on the shield gate.
Keep it tight, and watch out
for those towers.
More fighters. Form out at six-five.
Sir, enemy fighters coming in.
Melshi! Melshi, come in.
Are you there?
Bodhi sent a signal from here.
He's patching us in.
But you guys have to open up
a line for the tower.
How? Please advise.
There's a master switch
at the base of the comm tower.
Master switch? Describe.
What are we looking for?
What does it look like?
The master switch? Where is it?
U-wings, reinforce
those troops on the beach.
All fighters, on me.
We have to shield them from air attack.
Troop reinforcements. Here we go.
For Jedha!
We're having no effect on that shield.
How much more can that thing take?
Stick close, Red Five.
Where are you goin'?
They're all over me.
I'm trying to lose them!
This is Red Five! I need help!
"Hyperspace tracking.
Navigational systems."
Two screens down.
"Structural engineering." Open that one.
I've got one on my tail!
I'm on him!
Project code names: "Stellarsphere,
Mark Omega, Pax Aurora."
"War-Mantle, Cluster Prism,
Blacksaber."
What?
"Stardust."
That's it.
How do you know that?
I know because it's me.
Hey, you! Identify yourself.
I can...
Incoming fire! Get cover!
K, we need the file
for Stardust.
Stardust.
That's it.
K?
Climb.
You can still send the plans to the fleet.
If they open the shield gate...
you can broadcast from the tower.
Locking the vault door now.
K?
K!
- Goodbye.
- K!
Sir, unauthorized access
at the data vault.
What?
It's just come in, sir.
Send my guard squadron into battle.
Two men with me, now.
Get that beach under control!
Bodhi, are you there?
Did you call the fleet?
I can't get to the shuttle.
I can't plug in.
You have to. They have to hit that gate.
If the shield's open,
we can send the plans.
General, behind you!
Step back.
We're going down!
Come on!
Melshi, Melshi.
Come in, please.
I'm tied in at my end.
I just need an open line.
Hang on.
The master switch.
It's over near that console.
I'm going!
I've got it!
Careful!
You okay?
Jyn!
I'm one with the Force,
the Force is with me.
Chirrut!
I'm one with the Force
and the Force is with me.
I'm one with the Force,
the Force is with me.
I'm one with the Force...
and the Force is with me.
I'm one with the Force,
Chirrut! Come back!
I'm one with the Force...
Yes!
Keep going! Keep going!
Cassian!
Chirrut! Come! Come with me!
Chirrut!
Chirrut.
Don't go. Don't go.
I'm here, I'm here.
It's okay.
It's okay. Look for the Force.
Chirrut.
And you will always find me.
The Force is with me
and I'm one with the Force.
Deflector shields down to 50%!
We're sustaining heavy damage!
There's no turning back now!
We have to press the attack!
Hit that opening!
We see it, Gold Leader.
Ion torpedoes away!
What's happening?
We've lost engine power, sir.
That Star Destroyer's disabled.
This is Rogue One calling
any Alliance ships that can hear me.
Is there anybody out there?
This is Rogue One.
Come in, over!
This is Admiral Raddus,
Rogue One. We hear you.
We have the plans.
They found the Death Star plans.
They have to transmit them
from the communications tower.
You have to take down the shield gate.
It's the only way
they're gonna get them through.
Call up a Hammerhead corvette.
I have an idea.
Stand by, Rogue One. We're on it.
This is for you, Galen.
The Force is with me,
and I'm one with the Force.
Corvette Five, locked on target!
Prepare for impact.
Sublight thrusters, full power!
Reset antenna alignment.
Reverse engines! Full power!
Antenna aligned.
Ready to transmit.
Who are you?
You know who I am.
I'm Jyn Erso.
Daughter of Galen and Lyra.
You've lost.
Oh, I have, have I?
My father's revenge.
He built a flaw in the Death Star.
He put a fuse in the middle
of your machine...
and I've just told the entire galaxy
how to light it.
The shield is up.
Your signal will never reach
the rebel base.
All your ships in the air
will be destroyed.
I lose nothing but time.
You, on the other hand...
die with the Rebellion.
Transmitting.
Admiral, receiving
transmission from Scarif.
Leave it, leave it!
That's it.
Let's go.
Transmission received.
Admiral, we have the plans!
She did it!
Do you think anybody's listening?
I do.
Someone's out there.
Sir, we're detecting a massive object
emerging from hyperspace.
Sir, shall I begin targeting their fleet?
Lord Vader will handle the fleet.
Target the base at Scarif,
single reactor ignition.
Yes, sir.
Come on.
You may fire when ready.
Commence primary ignition.
Rogue One, may the Force be with you.
All ships prepare
for jump to hyperspace.
Your father would have been
proud of you, Jyn.
The rebel
flagship is disabled, my lord...
but has received transmissions
from the surface.
Prepare a boarding party.
Yes, my lord.
Hurry!
Let's go! We gotta go, now!
Move! Move! Move!
Hurry. Let's go!
Let's go!
It's stuck!
Hey!
Hey! Help!
Open fire!
Help us!
It's jammed!
Pull it!
Here! Here!
Take it! Take it!
Launch!
Make sure you secure the airlock.
And prepare the escape pods.
Your highness.
The transmission we received.
What is it they've sent us?
Hope.